SEPTEMBER 2020
To your places.
Prepare to shoot.
Units in position.
Report, please.
Unidentified creature reported.
Stay on high alert.
-It's out, sir!
-Is it human?
I can't tell, sir.
I can't see clearly because of the snow.
Moving in for closer visual.
It looks human!
Visibility is compromised.
Remain on standby
until visual is confirmed.
It keeps approaching, sir!
What should we do?
Units on standby at the bridge.
Standby to shoot.
Do not approach.
If you don't stop, we will shoot.
Alpha Team is ready, over.
Snipers in position.
Visual confirmed.
Ready to fire.
Fire!
Someone once said
that even the thickest darkness
disappears with the faintest light.
This is a story about us,
the ones trying to find
a reason to live
in a world where this is even harder
than merely surviving.
ORIGINAL STORY SWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
AUGUST 2020
CANCEL THE REDEVELOPMENT
INELIGIBLE UNION MEMBERS HAVE NO SAY
IN GREEN HOME REDEVELOPMENT
PROTECT OUR RIGHT TO LIVE
GREEN HOME RESIDENTS
Oh, my goodness. That was close.
I don't know how that flew
all the way over there.
I'm sorry. This isn't my job,
but they said nobody else
could work on the weekend.
People here think security guards
are slaves or something…
Well, anyway…
Excuse me.
I haven't seen you before.
What brings you here?
I moved…
What? I can't hear you.
Can you speak louder?
I moved here.
Moved?
I heard somebody was moving
into Room 1410. I guess that's you.
Are you living alone?
Yes.
What? I can't hear you.
I'm living alone.
Right.
BEAUTIFUL AND CLEAN
GREEN HOME MANAGEMENT OFFICE
Should I just die?
Mister!
Oh, right.
You're always sleeping.
-Do you ever work?
-I'm sorry.
Take the bed out.
Pardon?
Someone made a complaint about the bed.
That bed is why you're not focused on work
and dozing off all day.
Well, but then how would I get any rest?
I'm telling you not to rest.
Got that?
Why can't he understand anything?
He's so loud and uncultured.
Oh, hello.
Don't mind him.
He just never learned any manners.
But you know, I used to live in Gangnam.
None of the security guards there
had beds in their offices.
Pardon?
I'm just saying.
But what brings you here?
Oh, this. Someone sent me some fish.
But you know, I only eat yellow corvinas.
You can have these.
You really didn't have to.
Thank you so much.
You know the term
"noblesse oblige," right?
-Have a nice day.
-Right. Thank you, ma'am.
I'll enjoy these. Thank you!
Fucking hell.
Damn it.
Hey!
Was this you?
No.
Maybe it was the gangster guy.
Did you see who did it?
No.
Do you want one?
Are you a loner?
I thought handsome guys
couldn't be loners.
Maybe you're just an asshole.
Don't die here.
You'll just cause trouble
for a lot of people here.
Find somewhere else to die.
What are you doing?
I asked you to come by the office,
but I guess you forgot.
You need to fill out
a registration document.
I'll go later.
I'm sorry about earlier.
Here.
All right.
Yes, Mom.
I'll go back if I fail this audition.
How many times do I have to tell you?
This is the last one.
Don't take back your word.
I'll get accepted for sure this time.
A sponsorship?
I'm not going to be a prostitute. Okay?
-Hello.
-Right.
I'm so hungry.
I'm doing all this to earn a living,
but I might starve to death.
What? Why am I suddenly
getting a nosebleed?
-What do you think?
-It sucks.
Are you really going to perform there?
Don't you have any pride?
Hey, my pride's not making me any money.
And they're paying me a lot.
I could sell my soul
for that kind of money.
Hey, I have to go to work. Bye.
I guess you just moved here.
Yes, I came just a week ago.
Sorry I didn't introduce
myself earlier. I'm in Room 1510.
It's nice to meet you.
Oh, dear! It's okay, Da-eun.
She's just a neighbor.
Sorry.
I guess I was a little loud.
I might have a lot to be sorry about
in the future, though.
It's all right.
How old is your baby?
My little princess is just one year old.
Hello!
Isn't she pretty?
Yes, she is.
Aren't you getting in?
Oh, I…
forgot my wallet at home.
I'll wait for you.
No, it's fine. Go ahead.
What's wrong with her?
It's all right. She's a kind person.
She lost her baby last year.
They say her stroller
rolled into the street
when she wasn't looking.
That's so sad.
God sometimes gives us hardships
that are hard to overcome.
But failing to overcome them
doesn't mean you should be criticized
or feared by others for it.
Yes. You're right.
Everything is God's will.
It's nice to meet you.
I'm Jung Jae-heon. I live in Room 1506.
Am I being overly friendly?
No, it's just that
my hand reeks of cigarettes.
Oh, all right.
I'm Yoon Ji-su.
I guess you play the guitar.
I play the bass.
Oh, right.
What do you do, then?
I'm a Korean language teacher.
I have a Bible because I'm going
to church today. Since it's Sunday.
-That's nice.
-Right.
THE HOLY BIBLE
I'm not a missionary or anything.
Right. I get it.
-Bye, then.
-Bye.
Don't come in.
-Your lesson fees.
-I already paid for them.
-Where did you get the money?
-I met a rich guy.
Tell me the truth.
If I tell you
would anything change?
Why are you so damn nosy?
I just yanked out the whiskers!
And then I skinned it with my knife.
Look. This is it.
You see this?
Did you catch this snake, too?
What are you talking about?
Oh, what's that?
It's a snake!
What are you doing?
-Hey!
-What? Is that a snake?
-What?
-Sir…
Oh, my gosh!
Hey! Get ready!
Why are you doing this to me?
I didn't do anything!
-Hey, this is dangerous.
-I don't know what it is,
but I'm sorry.
I won't report this.
I won't tell anyone about this.
Are you really going to leave?
Don't you remember?
When you were a fourth grader…
What? What is that?
Please don't kill me.
I'm trying.
CONGRATULATIONS!
YOU'VE BEEN CHOSEN TO BE A TESTER
FOR THE REMAKE OF LAST WORLD
COME TO THE FAN FESTIVAL
AT G-TOWER ON AUGUST 25TH
AUGUST
NAME OF EVENT
AUGUST 25TH, TUESDAY
SUICIDE
DO NOT ENTER
What is this?
Is he unemployed?
He does look like a gangster, though.
Do you even pay rent?
Go and ask questions at school.
I got kicked out
for setting the school on fire.
It's been a week since I moved here.
I've only eaten ramyeon,
so I don't feel well.
But that doesn't matter.
I'm going to kill myself anyway.
OPEN
This is so hard. I didn't lose any weight.
This is so irritating.
Hey, Kitty.
I'm starving, but you're eating
as much as you want.
Hello? Oh, hi!
Oh, it's all right. Maybe next time…
Drinks?
Yes, I enjoy drinking.
All right, call me anytime.
I KEEP HEARING THINGS
AND GETTING NOSEBLEEDS
Damn it. What do I do?
SHOULD I SEE A DOCTOR?
IT'S REALLY SERIOUS.
Damn it…
WHAT THE HELL, WHO SAID TO LEAVE?
THAT PRICK EVEN MOVED
BECAUSE HIS PARENTS DIED
REST IN PEACE
HE'S THE ONLY ONE WHO SURVIVED
FIGURES
DON'T DIE UNTIL WE ALLOW YOU TO
YOU PRICK
THE SECURITY GUARD WASN'T IN
SO I LEFT YOUR PACKAGE AT THE DOOR
RAMYEON
What the hell?
Hungry…
Excuse me.
Are you in?
Please help me.
I'm so scared. Please help me.
Is there nobody home?
Please. Help me.
Please.
Hello?
Please help me.
I'm scared.
Hello?
Are you okay?
You're home.
Did something happen?
I just came home,
and the door was open,
and it was a mess inside.
And my cat is gone.
The floor…
It was covered in blood.
Please, help me.
Okay, calm down.
I'll call the police.
Can't you stay with me?
What's going on?
Please…
Hang on.
Please, can you open the door?
I'm so scared.
Please, can you stay with me? Please?
Please.
Please open the door.
Open the door. Please.
Well…
Can you show me your arms?
What?
Your arms.
Show me your arms.
What did you say?
Your arms.
Show me your arms.
I told you to open the door! Open it!
Open the door!
You asshole!
It's blood.
There's a lot of blood.
Did you
see a weird woman just now?
Jeez.
I shouldn't have played so much.
Coming.
You must be pretty angry.
I'm sorry. I sometimes get
really inspired at night, so…
-I'm hungry.
-What?
Open the door!
Your face…
Did you hurt yourself?
I'll be quiet!
I told you I'm sorry.
You're being a bit harsh!
Open the door!
I'm hungry!
Damn it…
SPORTS MEDICINE
MATH
I'm going to work now.
Don't just eat ramyeon, okay?
BASTARD
Eat a proper meal, all right?
And if you're not home later,
I'm reporting you missing.
Just report me as dead.
You're smothering me as it is.
LEE EUN-HYEOK
KEEP OUT
UNDER MAINTENANCE
Some woman was banging on the door,
and she had blood all over her face.
She seemed hurt, but she was so angry
and she was banging
on the door really hard…
You don't think she jumped, do you?
She wasn't just banging.
She was ramming into the door.
Damn it. I'm late.
What's going on?
Where's the security guard?
My daughter hasn't come home yet.
Who lowered the shutters?
Excuse me.
Does your cell have service?
I guess not.
What's going on here?
-Did you just come down?
-Yes.
Didn't you see anything strange
on the way?
-Like what?
-Never mind.
I asked what's going on.
We're trying to find out.
The back doors and the parking lot doors
are locked as well.
Are you saying we're locked in?
Someone may have locked us in.
Hey!
-Hey!
-Honey, just wait.
-Isn't anyone inside?
-Honey…
Ma'am, we can't just sit around
and wait forever. This is so annoying.
These jerks are going to ruin
our business. Damn it.
Honey…
I took photos
as evidence.
Is it still not open yet?
What…
Wait!
What are you doing?
Move if you're not going to help.
We'll have to pay to get the door fixed!
-Are you going to pay for it all?
-Excuse me.
Who's that? Hey! What the heck?
Oh, watch out!
Are you okay, sir?
Your hair.
That little jerk.
MANAGEMENT OFFICE
So they went home? I can't believe them…
Hello, this is Firefighter Seo Yi-kyung…
Every operator is currently busy
with disaster reports.
Please wait a moment.
Every operator is currently busy
with disaster reports.
-Please wait a moment.
-Landline phones must be working.
Every operator is currently busy
with disaster reports.
Please…
Did you just touch something?
Hey, you little…
I'm trying to open the doors!
-Put it back to how it was.
-Fine!
Maybe it wasn't that.
Oh, whatever.
The employees will fix the phone tomorrow.
That's not the point
when we're locked in here.
Is that it?
I found the switches!
All right, now we're ready.
The shutters will go up now.
We found the switch.
-Come on.
-Let's go.
-Let's open it.
-Why were they down?
I don't know. But all we had to do
was press a button.
I guess we can go out now.
What's that?
Okay, raise the main door switch…
And press this.
What's wrong with that guy?
It's open, right?
You're all getting out thanks to me.
Is that blood on his mouth?
Put it back down.
Oh my god.
Lower the shutters!
Help…
Mister!
When I signal you, lower the shutters!
Okay!
Honey!
Mister!
Lower it!
MAIN DOORS
Now!
Hurry!
Hurry! Come on!
Thank you.
What was that?
It wasn't human.
Is it gone?
-I don't know.
-I guess it's gone.
Go slowly.
Hey.
I heard you're a firefighter.
What's the government doing?
I'm sure they'll take care of things.
We're paying so much tax.
They can't even take care of one monster?
No.
It's not just one.
Protein!
What's going on?
I don't know.
Maybe the world
is finally coming to an end.
BASED ON SWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
Subtitle translation by Ju-young Park
Modify by Blue-Bird™